<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Build Intelligent Apps On Azure Blog</title>
        <link>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA</link>
        <description>Build Intelligent Apps On Azure Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 09:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1-2. Harnessing the Power of Intelligent Apps]]></title>
            <link>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/harnessing-the-power-of-intelligent-apps</link>
            <guid>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/harnessing-the-power-of-intelligent-apps</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This article explores real-world examples of how Intelligent Apps revolutionize logistics, retail, finance, manufacturing, tech, and medicine.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Explore real-world examples of how <strong>Intelligent Apps</strong> revolutionize <em>logistics</em>, <em>retail</em>, <em>finance</em>, <em>manufacturing</em>, <em>tech</em>, and <em>medicine</em>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-well-cover">What We'll Cover:<a href="#what-well-cover" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What We'll Cover:" title="Direct link to What We'll Cover:">​</a></h2><ul><li>Real-world businesses revolutionizing operations with Intelligent Apps</li><li>High level architecture for industry scenarios</li><li>Implementation architecture overview across industries</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A decorative header image for the blog" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/blog-image-1-dae57df4e529f1e89e0fe48a5932514e.png" width="624" height="380" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="real-world-success-stories">Real-world Success Stories<a href="#real-world-success-stories" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Real-world Success Stories" title="Direct link to Real-world Success Stories">​</a></h2><p>According to IBM’s 2022 <a href="https://www.ibm.com/downloads/cas/GVAGA3JP?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Global AI Adoption Index</a>, 35% of surveyed companies already use AI in their business, and 42% are exploring the idea. Organizations lagging behind the AI curve will quickly fall behind early adopters, who are already enjoying its benefits and boosting their investment in this technology.</p><p>In the first part of this series, <a href="https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/demystifying-intelligent-applications" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“Demystifying Intelligent Applications: Leveraging AI in App Development,”</a> we explored how organizations can use AI-powered apps, or intelligent apps, to transform their operations, decision-making, and customer experiences, leaping ahead of the competition.</p><p>Intelligent apps significantly improve operational efficiency and customer engagement across industries like logistics, retail, finance, manufacturing, tech, and healthcare. In this article, we’ll spotlight real-world success stories of businesses revolutionizing operations with intelligent apps using Microsoft Azure’s app, data, and AI services.</p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-info alert alert--info admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 14 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M7 2.3c3.14 0 5.7 2.56 5.7 5.7s-2.56 5.7-5.7 5.7A5.71 5.71 0 0 1 1.3 8c0-3.14 2.56-5.7 5.7-5.7zM7 1C3.14 1 0 4.14 0 8s3.14 7 7 7 7-3.14 7-7-3.14-7-7-7zm1 3H6v5h2V4zm0 6H6v2h2v-2z"></path></svg></span>info</div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p><strong>Register</strong> for the <a href="https://aka.ms/contoso-real-estate/learn-live?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn Live</a> on <strong>September 21</strong> for a live guided experience with SMEs on how to build end-to-end solution architecture for real world implementation of Intelligent Apps.</p></div></div><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="streamlining-operations-intelligent-apps-in-the-airline-industry">Streamlining Operations: Intelligent Apps in the Airline Industry<a href="#streamlining-operations-intelligent-apps-in-the-airline-industry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Streamlining Operations: Intelligent Apps in the Airline Industry" title="Direct link to Streamlining Operations: Intelligent Apps in the Airline Industry">​</a></h2><p>Aerospace pioneer Airbus <a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/en-us/story/858578-airbus-defense-and-intelligence-azure?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">leveraged intelligent apps to streamline its operations and innovate its services</a> with two ground-breaking modernizations that use Azure apps, data, and AI services to reimagine pilot training and predict aircraft maintenance issues.  </p><p>Aviation technology’s rapid evolution compelled Airbus to reconceive their approach to training pilots. The aircraft manufacturer created a pilot training chatbot by combining <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/ai-services?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure AI Services</a> with <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/ai-services/speech-to-text?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Speech to Text</a> and <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/ai-services/text-to-speech?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Text to Speech</a>. The bot helps trainee pilots navigate over 6,000 pages of technical information. Pilots can ask questions verbally for quick answers, aiding their understanding of dense information and speeding up training. And when Airbus needed to accommodate its military consumers, deploying its Kubernetes cluster to a disconnected, “air-gapped” environment met the strict security requirements of military aircraft training.</p><p>A chatbot could look like the following diagram as Azure services work together to create a conversational experience. Its components could include security and governance, bot logic and user experience (UX), bot cognition and intelligence, data extract, transfer, and load (ETL) operations, quality assurance and enhancements, logging, and monitoring and reporting.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A diagram of a conversational experience enabled by Azure services" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/blog-image-2-41c2cbd589f1701097f542c9660852e7.png" width="624" height="338" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Airbus also used AI to improve its aircraft maintenance and safety. They deployed <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/ai-services/ai-anomaly-detector?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AI Anomaly Detector</a> to gather and analyze telemetry data from multiple flights, enabling more profound insights into wear and tear on military aircraft operating in harsh conditions. This AI application helps Airbus better understand each airplane’s health. Airbus can predict and fix potential problems before they occur, improving the aircraft’s safety and operational readiness.</p><p>AI and Azure are changing how organizations like Airbus operate, even in strict, highly regulated markets with stringent security requirements. And by streamlining pilot training and staying ahead of aircraft maintenance, Airbus helps its military and commercial clients reliably deliver their goods across the globe, maintaining their critical supply chains.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="boosting-customer-service-intelligent-apps-in-the-retail-industry">Boosting Customer Service: Intelligent Apps in the Retail Industry<a href="#boosting-customer-service-intelligent-apps-in-the-retail-industry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Boosting Customer Service: Intelligent Apps in the Retail Industry" title="Direct link to Boosting Customer Service: Intelligent Apps in the Retail Industry">​</a></h2><p>The retail industry has been among the first to adopt and benefit from intelligent apps. For example, the leading American used car retailer, CarMax, <a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/en-us/story/1501304071775762777-carmax-retailer-azure-openai-service?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">uses intelligent apps to transform the car shopping experience</a>.</p><p>Before embracing AI, CarMax faced a significant challenge: Manually creating text summaries was time-consuming and labor-intensive. CarMax decided to leverage <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/ai-services/openai-service?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure OpenAI Service</a> to automatically generate car research pages, offering customers valuable insights while enhancing the website’s search engine rankings.</p><p>This AI-driven approach has significantly streamlined the process, achieving in a few months what would have taken years manually. Also, the AI system condenses thousands of customer reviews into a few readable sentences, offering potential buyers a quick overview of others’ experiences.</p><p>CarMax has improved their customer experience while boosting operational efficiency through AI adoption. CarMax’s editorial staff focuses on creating strategic, longer-form content with the time saved, enhancing productivity, and driving more website traffic.</p><p>CarMax’s success story serves as a testament to the potential of intelligent apps in the retail industry.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enhancing-cybersecurity-intelligent-apps-in-finance">Enhancing Cybersecurity: Intelligent Apps in Finance<a href="#enhancing-cybersecurity-intelligent-apps-in-finance" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enhancing Cybersecurity: Intelligent Apps in Finance" title="Direct link to Enhancing Cybersecurity: Intelligent Apps in Finance">​</a></h2><p>Intelligent apps also impact the highly regulated financial services sector. Swift, a leading infrastructure provider for financial messaging services, <a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/en-us/story/1637929534319366070-swift-banking-capital-markets-azure-machine-learning?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">uses intelligent apps to enhance decision-making and combat financial crime</a>.</p><p>The massive growth of cross-border transactions and instant payment networks led to a surge in financial fraud that can cost the industry hundreds of billions of dollars every year. So, Swift and Microsoft partnered to build an anomaly detection model using <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/ai-machine-learning-blog/federated-learning-with-azure-machine-learning-powering-privacy/ba-p/3824720" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">federated learning techniques</a> with <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/machine-learning/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Machine Learning</a> and <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/solutions/confidential-compute/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure confidential computing</a>.</p><p><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/purview/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Purview</a> helped govern data, as the federated learning method partially trained each model in a silo before aggregating them. This approach enabled Swift and Microsoft to develop a highly accurate model without copying or moving data from Swift members’ secure locations, ensuring the highest level of security and privacy.</p><p>Financial organizations can now deploy this trained ML model to run a real-time fraud detection system, lowering the cost of financial fraud.</p><p>Organizations can deploy a fraud detection system like the following example on Microsoft Azure. The system ingests data from streams or storage, runs analytics, and uses ML to detect fraud and store results. It then alerts users and other systems to the security issue.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A diagram of an example fraud detection system" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/blog-image-3-122e6e30b6e98b3caf9d9de89bf5e9cf.png" width="624" height="480" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Swift provides the innovative model to its banking partners, who can share data to further train the model. Azure confidential computing securely runs new models on current data to accumulate insights, generating an ongoing learning cycle. This iterative approach strengthens the global detection of fraudulent financial transactions through an increasingly faster and more accurate model.  </p><p>The collaboration between Swift and Microsoft demonstrates how combining various Azure services creates Intelligent Apps to enhance decision-making in finance. These apps solve real problems at an unprecedented global scale.  </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enhancing-efficiency-intelligent-apps-in-manufacturing">Enhancing Efficiency: Intelligent Apps in Manufacturing<a href="#enhancing-efficiency-intelligent-apps-in-manufacturing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enhancing Efficiency: Intelligent Apps in Manufacturing" title="Direct link to Enhancing Efficiency: Intelligent Apps in Manufacturing">​</a></h2><p>3M, known for Post-it Notes and other innovative products, <a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/en-us/story/1504342377134122633-3M-manufacturing-azure-machine-learning?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wielded the power of Intelligent Apps to standardize, automate, and accelerate its sales forecasting</a>. The company needed a unified, automated approach to replace its multiple manual methods.</p><p>It adopted Azure Machine Learning and other Azure AI Services to develop, train, and implement 1,500 custom models for each region and division, replacing manual methods. This solution delivers timely finance, sales, and marketing insights while freeing teams from time-consuming manual data manipulation tasks.</p><p>3M used Azure Machine Learning, <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/machine-learning/automatedml/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">automated machine learning</a> (AutoML), and the <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/solution-accelerator-many-models" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Many Models Solution Accelerator</a> to train and score numerous machine learning models in parallel. This approach significantly shortened the company’s development cycle time.</p><p>Then, 3M integrated <a href="https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Power BI</a> into their solution to compile and visualize results more effectively. Executives now have an unbiased and unfiltered view of data for better decision-making. With its improved ability to forecast sales, 3M can focus on manufacturing the products it needs efficiently.</p><p>3M’s success demonstrates how combining various Azure services can enhance efficiency in the manufacturing industry. These apps improve operational processes while enabling employees to focus on higher-level tasks. Strategic decisions are more targeted, and business conversations are more meaningful.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="driving-innovation-intelligent-apps-in-the-technology-industry">Driving Innovation: Intelligent Apps in the Technology Industry<a href="#driving-innovation-intelligent-apps-in-the-technology-industry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Driving Innovation: Intelligent Apps in the Technology Industry" title="Direct link to Driving Innovation: Intelligent Apps in the Technology Industry">​</a></h2><p>As expected, the tech industry is at the forefront of leveraging Intelligent Apps to drive innovation. Elastic <a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/en-us/story/1653495116803202350-elastic-partner-professional-services-azure-openai-service?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">saw an opportunity to use intelligent apps to optimize its search services and meet customer needs more effectively</a>. The company built a managed, secure, and scalable solution for its customers, Elastic Cloud, by leveraging <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Azure</a>.</p><p>Elastic Cloud uses Azure Machine Learning and other Azure AI Services to automate many basic management tasks, such as backing up data, upgrading, and scaling deployments. This approach enables Elastic’s customers to focus less on managing the software and more on serving their own clients. Customers can quickly deploy and manage Elastic Cloud on Kubernetes (ECK) using <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/kubernetes-service/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Kubernetes Service</a>.</p><p>As a result, Elastic’s cloud business is growing twice as fast as its on-premises solutions. Enterprise search users have reported significant improvements in system availability and employee satisfaction.</p><p>Additionally, Elastic incorporated Azure OpenAI Service into its Elasticsearch Relevance Engine (ESRE), providing more relevant answers to search queries. ESRE enables text, vector, and hybrid search, offering a more effective and accurate response to queries.</p><p>Elastic’s success story demonstrates how combining various Azure services can create intelligent Apps to drive innovation in the tech industry. These apps help improve operational processes and deliver better results quickly.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="revolutionizing-healthcare-intelligent-apps-in-medicine">Revolutionizing Healthcare: Intelligent Apps in Medicine<a href="#revolutionizing-healthcare-intelligent-apps-in-medicine" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Revolutionizing Healthcare: Intelligent Apps in Medicine" title="Direct link to Revolutionizing Healthcare: Intelligent Apps in Medicine">​</a></h2><p>Intelligent apps also drive transformative changes in the healthcare sector. Cambridgeshire and Peterborough NHS Foundation Trust, a healthcare provider in the United Kingdom, gradually shifted their on-premises systems to the cloud using Azure, improving flexibility, and lowering costs. They needed a solution for their electronic patient record (EPR) system that integrates 23 years of data across multiple systems and formats.</p><p>The Trust used Microsoft Azure and <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/ai-services/cognitive-search?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Cognitive Search</a>, including semantic search for understanding intent and contexts and cognitive capabilities for extracting insights from data, to <a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/en-us/story/1612121636839251558-cpft-health-provider-azure-en-united-kingdom?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">standardize and automate data management</a>. This approach made legacy, archive, and live data more discoverable, saving clinicians’ time. The Trust’s solution searches through millions of clinical documents in seconds, even recognizing handwritten notes without needing a separate optical character recognition (OCR) solution to extract text from images (Azure Cognitive Search automatically does it). Clinicians can now uncover previously inaccessible insights, enabling them to offer more personalized care.</p><p>The Trust also used <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/category/integration/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Integration Services</a> tools such as <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/logic-apps/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Logic Apps</a> to create workflows without writing code and <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/event-grid/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Event Grid</a> to connect Azure and third-party services through a <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/architecture/patterns/publisher-subscriber?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">publisher-subscriber model</a>. They switched on a live feed from their new EPR system to Azure to feed real-time information into other applications. Researchers can now access anonymized data to fuel medical innovations beyond the NHS.</p><p>The healthcare provider also invested heavily in Power BI’s data visualization and analytical functions to sift through massive amounts of information. This level of data accessibility was previously impossible with their on-premises system. The new insights have significantly improved clinicians’ efficiency for better patient care.</p><p>Data accessibility and security are critical in the healthcare industry. Intelligent Apps empower organizations like the Trust to revolutionize medical care. AI capabilities helped the Trust improve its operational efficiency and user experiences, setting a new standard for healthcare in the digital age.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="summary">Summary<a href="#summary" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Summary" title="Direct link to Summary">​</a></h2><p>AI is driving transformation and real-world successes across industries. Intelligent apps are reshaping our world by streamlining operations in manufacturing and logistics, enhancing customer experience in the retail sector, improving decision-making in finance, driving innovation in tech, and revolutionizing healthcare.</p><p>As organizations adopt AI, they’re innovating in ways that were once too difficult, expensive, or outright impossible. Companies that wait to embrace intelligent apps risk the chance of falling behind. By embracing intelligent apps and leveraging the capabilities of Azure, you can harness the transformative potential of AI to remain on the cutting edge of technology.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="exercise">Exercise<a href="#exercise" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Exercise" title="Direct link to Exercise">​</a></h2><ul><li><strong>Complete</strong> the <a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/apps-csc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intelligent Apps Cloud Skills Challenge</a> to build on your to build your fundamentals for AI app development.</li><li><strong>Watch</strong> <a href="https://aka.ms/learnlive-contoso-app-deconstructed-Ep1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Episode 01</a> of the Serverless Edition Learn Live session to learn how to build an end-to-end intelligent app solution.</li><li><strong>Register</strong> for the <a href="https://info.microsoft.com/ww-landing-driving-business-value-by-modernizing-with-cloud-native-and-ai.html?lcid=en-us?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intelligent Apps webinar</a> with Microsoft and Forrester.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Fall-For-IA</category>
            <category>30-days-of-IA</category>
            <category>learn-live</category>
            <category>hack-together</category>
            <category>community-buzz</category>
            <category>ask-the-expert</category>
            <category>azure-kubernetes-service</category>
            <category>azure-functions</category>
            <category>azure-openai</category>
            <category>azure-container-apps</category>
            <category>azure-cosmos-db</category>
            <category>github-copilot</category>
            <category>github-codespaces</category>
            <category>github-actions</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1-1. Demystifying Intelligent Applications]]></title>
            <link>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/demystifying-intelligent-applications</link>
            <guid>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/demystifying-intelligent-applications</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This article explores the concept of intelligent applications for readers, providing a clear understanding of the role of AI capabilities in modern applications.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let’s start with understanding the <strong>power of intelligent applications</strong>. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-well-cover">What We'll Cover:<a href="#what-well-cover" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What We'll Cover:" title="Direct link to What We'll Cover:">​</a></h2><ul><li>What are intelligent applications?</li><li>Categories of Intelligent Apps</li><li>Breaking down the role of AI in intelligent apps</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A decorative header image for the blog" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/blog-image1-693e85646492f1adfe66b034cce9edb0.png" width="624" height="380" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="demystifying-intelligent-applications-leveraging-ai-in-app-development">Demystifying Intelligent Applications: Leveraging AI in App Development<a href="#demystifying-intelligent-applications-leveraging-ai-in-app-development" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Demystifying Intelligent Applications: Leveraging AI in App Development" title="Direct link to Demystifying Intelligent Applications: Leveraging AI in App Development">​</a></h2><p>Until recent years, when you heard the term “artificial intelligence” (AI), you might have pictured autonomous robots from sci-fi films. Now, perhaps your mind jumps to big data and machine learning (ML). Maybe you’re even thinking about the latest ChatGPT plugins and transformer architectures. Today, AI is more than these imaginations: it’s a reality increasingly woven into our day-to-day routines through intelligent applications.</p><p>Intelligent apps combine cloud-scale compute, data, and predictive or generative AI. These applications help you automate tasks and make data-driven decisions, aiding in leveraging business intelligence to gain meaningful, practical outcomes.  </p><p>For developers, the AI landscape isn’t an abstract complexity. It’s a real, tangible opportunity for evolving traditional applications, making them “intelligent,” and delivering more value to users. And with tools like Azure Kubernetes Service, Azure Cosmos DB, and <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/solutions/ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure AI Services</a>, stepping into the world of intelligent apps isn’t a steep climb but a steady trek across a manageable learning curve.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-three-categories-of-intelligent-applications">The Three Categories of Intelligent Applications<a href="#the-three-categories-of-intelligent-applications" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Three Categories of Intelligent Applications" title="Direct link to The Three Categories of Intelligent Applications">​</a></h2><p>Before we start building, it’s critical to understand what makes an app “intelligent.” It’s not a universal definition so much as an identifier for apps that fall into one or more of the three primary categories:  </p><ul><li><p><strong>Outcome-based</strong> — This designation represents the broadest category of intelligent apps, whose principal value for users is the intelligent outcomes they provide. These apps process data to provide insightful results that enhance decision-making or help with tasks like trend prediction, resource management, and customer relationship management.</p></li><li><p><strong>Functionality-based</strong> — This type of intelligent app takes AI integration a degree further, integrating AI as a function of the app to create or process its outputs, enhancing the app’s overall interactivity and usefulness.</p></li><li><p><strong>Feature-based</strong> — This is the narrowest category, in which the app’s AI/ML component is one of its core features and primary selling points</p></li></ul><p>Let’s dive more deeply into each category.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="outcome-based-apps-intelligent-outcomes-drive-success">Outcome-Based Apps: Intelligent Outcomes Drive Success<a href="#outcome-based-apps-intelligent-outcomes-drive-success" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Outcome-Based Apps: Intelligent Outcomes Drive Success" title="Direct link to Outcome-Based Apps: Intelligent Outcomes Drive Success">​</a></h2><p>Outcome-based applications are all about the results provided to the user. They function beyond merely processing data to offer insightful outcomes that drive success.</p><p>Think of a personal fitness tracker app that uses AI to analyze the user’s activity and provides actionable recommendations for achieving a goal. This type of app not only tracks your steps, sleep patterns, and heart rate but uses that data to provide you with personalized health advice. It helps you make informed lifestyle choices — the “intelligent” outcome.</p><p>Another example is a social media marketing app that uses AI for time-saving data analysis, task automation, and trend prediction. AI-based sentiment analysis can gauge customer perception while natural language processing (NLP) accurately interprets customer inquiries. Task automation can schedule posts and automate responses to common customer queries, and trend forecasting helps model and predict customer behavior to further personalize targeted promotional efforts. Building this type of intelligence into your apps provides cost-effective, actionable insights that guide sales and marketing strategies.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="functionality-based-apps-ai-driven-features-enhance-user-experiences">Functionality-Based Apps: AI-Driven Features Enhance User Experiences<a href="#functionality-based-apps-ai-driven-features-enhance-user-experiences" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Functionality-Based Apps: AI-Driven Features Enhance User Experiences" title="Direct link to Functionality-Based Apps: AI-Driven Features Enhance User Experiences">​</a></h2><p>As the name suggests, functionality-based applications integrate AI into how the app functions, but the end user drives the action and outcome. In this category of apps, AI takes a more active role in the user’s interaction by allowing them to use AI-created or processed output. These apps leverage AI technologies like <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/cognitive-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure AI Services</a> for NLP, image recognition, and pattern recognition to improve user experience.</p><p>Consider a music app that generates personalized playlists based on your listening habits or your smartphone’s camera app that uses AI to recognize faces and optimize photo settings. Even more advanced are the language translation apps that translate text from one language to another and can even understand and maintain the context and subtleties of the conversation. They use NLP to accomplish these feats.</p><p>Similarly, consider the latest e-commerce apps, whose AI-driven functionalities enable customers to try on clothes virtually, significantly enhancing the online shopping experience.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="feature-based-apps-integrating-advanced-aiml-components">Feature-Based Apps: Integrating Advanced AI/ML Components<a href="#feature-based-apps-integrating-advanced-aiml-components" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Feature-Based Apps: Integrating Advanced AI/ML Components" title="Direct link to Feature-Based Apps: Integrating Advanced AI/ML Components">​</a></h2><p>Finally, there are feature-based intelligent apps. These apps incorporate advanced AI/ML components like neural networks, internal large language models (LLMs), and sophisticated algorithms as core features for the user. In this type of application, AI is the primary feature for users to engage with and the primary selling point for the app.</p><p>Some examples of feature-based applications are chatbots and virtual agents built using <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-ca/products/bot-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Bot Service</a>. These robo-representatives use AI to provide more natural and human-like conversation, balancing superior efficiency with a friendlier, more personalized user experience. <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/edge/features/the-new-bing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The new Bing</a> is a prime example of this implementation, integrating AI to give users a knowledgeable copilot for web searches.</p><p>Similarly, OpenAI’s <a href="https://openai.com/chatgpt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ChatGPT</a> allows users access to its state-of-the-art language models available as Microsoft’s <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/cognitive-services/openai-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure OpenAI Service</a>. It leverages the power of the highly sophisticated GPT-3 LLM to perform tasks like drafting emails, writing code, answering general knowledge questions, translating between languages, and tutoring in numerous subjects.</p><p>These apps don’t just use AI to provide outputs or improve user experiences: They push the boundaries of what’s possible in app development by integrating AI/ML components.</p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-info alert alert--info admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 14 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M7 2.3c3.14 0 5.7 2.56 5.7 5.7s-2.56 5.7-5.7 5.7A5.71 5.71 0 0 1 1.3 8c0-3.14 2.56-5.7 5.7-5.7zM7 1C3.14 1 0 4.14 0 8s3.14 7 7 7 7-3.14 7-7-3.14-7-7-7zm1 3H6v5h2V4zm0 6H6v2h2v-2z"></path></svg></span>info</div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p><strong>Register</strong> for the live Q&amp;A <a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/ATE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask The Expert session</a> on <strong>September 26</strong> with the  Azure Functions product engineering team.</p></div></div><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="breaking-down-the-role-of-ai-in-intelligent-applications">Breaking Down the Role of AI in Intelligent Applications<a href="#breaking-down-the-role-of-ai-in-intelligent-applications" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Breaking Down the Role of AI in Intelligent Applications" title="Direct link to Breaking Down the Role of AI in Intelligent Applications">​</a></h2><p>Intelligent apps reflect the merging of traditional software design with the dynamic capabilities of AI. Let’s explore how AI integrates and amplifies these applications.</p><p>At its core, AI augments applications with the capacity to self-learn and self-improve. It allows you to create applications that predict, react, and adapt to a constantly changing environment. In the power grid management system for a major city, an AI-infused application can forecast power usage trends, react to anomalies, and adapt to sudden demand surges, ensuring optimal efficiency and preventing blackouts.</p><p>But AI’s role doesn’t end at prediction or decision-making: It also automates tasks. In enterprise solutions, it has moved beyond simple automation to encompass intelligent process automation (IPA). In this arena, AI algorithms understand, learn, and then automate entire digital workflows. For developers, this is a fertile ground for creating applications that can dramatically improve the operational efficiency of businesses.</p><p>Even more, AI substantially aids in development tasks. For example, there’s <a href="https://github.com/features/copilot" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub Copilot</a>, an AI-powered code assistant that offers suggestions based not only on syntax but on development best practices and the intent of the code. AI has evolved from a tool you use to build apps to a partner that helps in creating them.  </p><p>Using AI to build intelligent apps isn’t about throwing out what’s worked before. It’s about enhancing the components that have the most impact and achieve the best results. Incorporating AI in apps elevates their predictive abilities, streamlines complex tasks, and even aids in the development and creation process. When you build intelligent apps, you don’t just address current problems. You anticipate future challenges and craft solutions that adapt over time.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="summary">Summary<a href="#summary" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Summary" title="Direct link to Summary">​</a></h2><p>As developers the power of AI is in our hands, and it’s our responsibility to harness its full potential. Each category tells the story of AI's transformative potential, from applications that deliver intelligent outcomes to those with AI capabilities to enrich the user experience and those pushing boundaries with advanced AI/ML technology.</p><p>Accessible and robust platforms like <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure AI</a> can simplify the process of developing Intelligent Applications. Whether you’re refining an existing app or building a new one, just entering the world of AI, or already familiar with the landscape, take a moment to appreciate the potential that AI integration offers. You’re embracing this exciting frontier and shaping the future of app development.  </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="exercise">Exercise<a href="#exercise" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Exercise" title="Direct link to Exercise">​</a></h2><ul><li><strong>Complete</strong> the <a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/csc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cloud Skills Challenge</a> to build on your apps and AI skills. </li><li>Watch <a href="https://aka.ms/learnlive-contoso-app-deconstructed-Ep1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Episode 01</a> of the Serverless Edition Learn Live session to learn how to build an end-to-end intelligent app solution.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Fall-For-IA</category>
            <category>30-days-of-IA</category>
            <category>learn-live</category>
            <category>hack-together</category>
            <category>community-buzz</category>
            <category>ask-the-expert</category>
            <category>azure-kubernetes-service</category>
            <category>azure-functions</category>
            <category>azure-openai</category>
            <category>azure-container-apps</category>
            <category>azure-cosmos-db</category>
            <category>github-copilot</category>
            <category>github-codespaces</category>
            <category>github-actions</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kick-off #30DaysofIA 🍂]]></title>
            <link>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/kick-off</link>
            <guid>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/kick-off</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This Fall focus on building intelligent apps using AI and cloud-native technologies. `#FallForIntelligentApps` brings to you a learning journey to build your skills on creating differentiated experiences while modernizing your applications. It’s time to `learn it all`.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This Fall focus on building intelligent apps using AI and cloud-native technologies. <code>#FallForIntelligentApps</code> brings to you a learning journey to build your skills on creating differentiated experiences while modernizing your applications. It’s time to <code>learn it all</code>. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-well-cover">What We'll Cover<a href="#what-well-cover" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What We'll Cover" title="Direct link to What We'll Cover">​</a></h2><ul><li>What is Fall For Intelligent Apps? </li><li>How Can I participate? </li><li>How Can I skill up? (in just 30 Days) </li><li><strong>Exercise:</strong> Take the <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/apps-csc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Fall For Intelligent Apps Skills Challenge</a></li><li><strong>Resources:</strong> <a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/collection/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#30DaysOfIA Collection</a></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="image" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/FallForIA_Key_visual-3fa668895eb8360fbc2714f2cd867168.jpg" width="1920" height="347" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="get-ready-to-fallforintelligentapps-starting-september-18">Get Ready To #FallForIntelligentApps starting September 18!<a href="#get-ready-to-fallforintelligentapps-starting-september-18" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Get Ready To #FallForIntelligentApps starting September 18!" title="Direct link to Get Ready To #FallForIntelligentApps starting September 18!">​</a></h2><p>Today, we kick off the Fall season with content and activities to skill you up on all things Intelligent Apps or AI Apps on Azure with content, events, and community interactions! Read on to learn about what is coming!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="explore-our-initiatives">Explore Our Initiatives<a href="#explore-our-initiatives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Explore Our Initiatives" title="Direct link to Explore Our Initiatives">​</a></h2><p>We have a number of initiatives planned for the month to help you learn and skill up on relevant technologies. Click on the links to visit the relevant pages for each</p><ul><li><a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/30days" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#30DaysOfIA</a> - 6 themed weeks of daily articles in a structured roadmap</li><li><a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/LearnLive" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn Live Series</a> – 8 weekly live episodes on <code>Serverless</code> and <code>Kubernetes</code></li><li><a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/ATE-series" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask The Expert</a> – join live Q&amp;A sessions with Product Engineering teams</li><li><a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/csc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cloud Skills Challenge</a> – skill up by competing with peers to complete modules</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="image" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/Website-kick-off-208698f62485b9185ffd346397147366.jpg" width="1280" height="720" class="img_ev3q"></p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-info alert alert--info admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 14 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M7 2.3c3.14 0 5.7 2.56 5.7 5.7s-2.56 5.7-5.7 5.7A5.71 5.71 0 0 1 1.3 8c0-3.14 2.56-5.7 5.7-5.7zM7 1C3.14 1 0 4.14 0 8s3.14 7 7 7 7-3.14 7-7-3.14-7-7-7zm1 3H6v5h2V4zm0 6H6v2h2v-2z"></path></svg></span><mdxadmonitiontitle><strong>Register for the events!</strong></mdxadmonitiontitle></div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p>What are 3 things you can do today, to jumpstart your learning journey?</p><ul><li>Register for live Q&amp;A sessions (free, online) <ul><li>September 26 – <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/ATE-series" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask The Expert: Azure Functions</a></li><li>October 11 – <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/ATE-series" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask The Expert: Azure App Service</a></li><li>October 18  - <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/ATE-series" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask The Expert: Azure Container Apps</a></li><li>October 25 – <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/ATE-series" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask The Expert: Azure Kubernetes Service</a></li></ul></li><li>Register for the <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/LearnLive" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn Live Series: Serverless Edition</a> – weekly live learning </li><li>Register for the <a href="https://info.microsoft.com/ww-landing-driving-business-value-by-modernizing-with-cloud-native-and-ai.html?lcid=en-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intelligent Apps webinar</a> with Microsoft and Forrester</li><li>Complete the <a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/csc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cloud Skills Challenge</a> – ends on October 31! </li></ul></div></div><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="30days-of-intelligent-apps">#30Days Of Intelligent Apps<a href="#30days-of-intelligent-apps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to #30Days Of Intelligent Apps" title="Direct link to #30Days Of Intelligent Apps">​</a></h2><p><a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/30days" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#30DaysOfIA</a> is a series of daily blog posts grouped into themed weeks - taking you from core concepts to end-to-end solution examples in 30 days. Each article will provide conceptual lessons paired with exercises and resources to help you reinforce learnings and take next steps.</p><p>This series takes you through learning journey in <strong>four stages</strong>, each building on the previous week to help you skill up in a beginner-friendly way:</p><ul><li><strong>Week 1</strong>: Power of <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/build-next-generation-ai-powered-applications-on-microsoft-azure/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intelligent Applications</a></li><li><strong>Week 2:</strong> How to build intelligent apps with <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/solutions/cloud-native-apps/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cloud-native</a>?</li><li><strong>Week 3:</strong> Powering intelligent applications using <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/aks/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Kubernetes Service</a></li><li><strong>Week 4:</strong> Building a Serverless Intelligent App with <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/functions-overview?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi&amp;pivots=programming-language-csharp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Functions</a> and <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/ai-services/openai/overview/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure OpenAI</a></li><li><strong>Week 5:</strong> Build end to end AI powered solutions with real world <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/architecture/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reference architectures</a></li><li><strong>Week 6:</strong> Build your own <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/training/paths/copilot/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Copilot</a></li></ul><p>We will start with defining intelligent apps and then expand on how to build with cloud-native technologies like <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/kubernetes-service/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Kubernetes Service</a>, <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/container-apps/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Container Apps</a> and <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/functions?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Functions</a>, and take you through end-to-end scenarios for real world application development. Before we dive deep on intelligent apps, here is a high-level overview of the <strong>Intelligent Apps</strong> landscape on Azure: </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="image" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/intelligent-apps-image-8b1a8023638a607ea9cf064df3a2dacc.jpg" width="1280" height="720" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Containers on Azure</strong> services offer you a wide range of capabilities, from simplicity to control to suit your different needs.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="image" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/Containers-on-Azure-98bc0be88024cfcfaab2150a56d0f9f9.jpg" width="1280" height="720" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" alt="image" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/Containers-on-Azure-2-d540131359e93ea0f5da8bc2082fec3d.jpg" width="1280" height="720" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>To start with the basics for developing <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/kubernetes-service/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes</a> applications, explore <a href="https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/cnny-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#30DaysOfCloudNative</a>.</p><p>Cloud-native development when paired with <strong>serverless computing</strong> enhances your solution architecture for building cost optimized, resilient applications.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="image" src="/Cloud-Native/assets/images/Serverless-New-f9eb0000337edcfd1c86e90460767400.jpg" width="1280" height="720" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>To start with the basics for <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/solutions/serverless/?WT.mc_id=javascript-99907-ninarasi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">serverless computing</a>, explore <a href="https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/blog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#30DaysOfServerless</a>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="lets-get-started">Let’s Get Started<a href="#lets-get-started" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Let’s Get Started" title="Direct link to Let’s Get Started">​</a></h2><p>Now you know everything! We hope you are as excited as we are to dive into a full month of active learning and doing! Don't forget to <a href="https://aka.ms/fallforIA/30days/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subscribe</a> for updates in your favorite feed reader! <strong>And look out for our first Intelligent Apps post Monday!</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Fall-For-IA</category>
            <category>30-days-of-IA</category>
            <category>learn-live</category>
            <category>hack-together</category>
            <category>community-buzz</category>
            <category>ask-the-expert</category>
            <category>azure-kubernetes-service</category>
            <category>azure-functions</category>
            <category>azure-openai</category>
            <category>azure-container-apps</category>
            <category>azure-cosmos-db</category>
            <category>github-copilot</category>
            <category>github-codespaces</category>
            <category>github-actions</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HackTogether Recap 🍂]]></title>
            <link>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/hacktogether-recap</link>
            <guid>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/hacktogether-recap</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Exciting news! As we approach the close of #JavaScript on #Azure Global Hack today, we are thrilled to announce another exciting opportunity for all JavaScript developers!! Find a recap of Hack together and read all about the upcoming #FallIntoIA on this post!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Continue The Learning Journey through <strong>Fall For Intelligent Apps!</strong> 🍂</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-well-cover">What We'll Cover<a href="#what-well-cover" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What We'll Cover" title="Direct link to What We'll Cover">​</a></h2><ul><li>Thank you! ♥️ </li><li>Recap of The <a href="https://aka.ms/JavaScripton_Azure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JavaScript on Azure Global Hack-Together</a></li><li>Continue the journey</li><li>Hands-on practice: Make your first contribution to open-source!</li><li>Resources: For self-study!</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="thank-you-️">Thank you! ♥️<a href="#thank-you-️" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Thank you! ♥️" title="Direct link to Thank you! ♥️">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/40116776/264592120-1dc08b59-0555-40b2-8866-59248a573b83.png" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>It's hard to believe that JavaScript on Azure hack-together is ending! It seems like just yesterday that we launched this initiative, and yet here we are, 15 days later, with an incredible amount of learning and growth behind us. So... it's time for a wrap!</p><p>From the bottom of our hearts, we want to thank each and every one of you for your participation, engagement, and enthusiasm. It's been truly inspiring to see the passion and dedication from this strong community, and we're honored to be a part of it. ✨</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="recap-of-the-javascript-on-azure-global-hack-together">Recap of The <a href="https://aka.ms/JavaScripton_Azure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JavaScript on Azure Global Hack-Together</a><a href="#recap-of-the-javascript-on-azure-global-hack-together" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to recap-of-the-javascript-on-azure-global-hack-together" title="Direct link to recap-of-the-javascript-on-azure-global-hack-together">​</a></h2><p>As we wrap up this exciting event, we wanted to take a moment to reflect on all that we've accomplished together. Over the last 15 days, we've covered a lot of ground, from the basics of contributing to Open source to the exploration of the Contoso Real Estate project from its Frontend to its Backend and future AI implementation.   </p><p>Now that the hack-together is ending, we want to make sure that you have all the resources you need to continue honing your skills in the future. Whether you're looking to make your fist contribution to open source, become an open source maintainers, collaborate with others, or simply keep learning, there are plenty of resources out there to help you achieve your goals. So, let's dive in and explore all the ways you can continue to grow your JavaScript skills on Azure!</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="jsonazure-hack-together-roadmap-">JSonAzure Hack-together Roadmap 📍:<a href="#jsonazure-hack-together-roadmap-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to JSonAzure Hack-together Roadmap 📍:" title="Direct link to JSonAzure Hack-together Roadmap 📍:">​</a></h3><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/40116776/264975573-85938fcc-b235-4b5b-b45a-f174d3cf560d.png" alt="hack-together-roadmap (2)" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="recap-on-past-livestreams">Recap on past Livestreams🌟:<a href="#recap-on-past-livestreams" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Recap on past Livestreams🌟:" title="Direct link to Recap on past Livestreams🌟:">​</a></h3><p>Day 1️⃣: <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/reactor/events/20275/?WT.mc_id=academic-98351-juliamuiruri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Opening Keynote (Hack-together Launch)</a>: Introduction to the Contoso Real Estate Open-source project!, managing complex and complex enterprise architecture, new announcements for JavaScript developers on Azure</p><p>Day 2️⃣: <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/reactor/events/20321/?WT.mc_id=academic-98351-juliamuiruri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub Copilot &amp; Codespaces</a>: Introduction to your AI pair programmer (GitHub Copilot) and your virtual developer environment on the cloud (GitHub Codespaces)</p><p>Day 6️⃣: <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/reactor/events/20276/?WT.mc_id=academic-98351-juliamuiruri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Build your Frontend using Static Web Apps</a> as part of a complex, modern composable frontends (or micro-frontends) and cloud-native applications.</p><p>Day 9️⃣: Build a Serverless Backend using <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/reactor/events/20277/?WT.mc_id=academic-98351-juliamuiruri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Functions</a></p><p>Day 1️⃣3️⃣: Easily connect to an <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/reactor/events/20278/?WT.mc_id=academic-98351-juliamuiruri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Cosmos DB</a>, exploring its benefits and how to get started</p><p>Day 1️⃣5️⃣: Being in the AI Era, we dive into the <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/reactor/events/20322/?WT.mc_id=academic-98351-juliamuiruri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure OpenAI Service</a> and how you can start to build intelligent JavaScript applications</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="-self-learning-resources">📖 Self-Learning Resources<a href="#-self-learning-resources" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 📖 Self-Learning Resources" title="Direct link to 📖 Self-Learning Resources">​</a></h3><ol><li>JavaScript on Azure Global Hack Together <a href="https://aka.ms/JavaScriptonAzureCSC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Module collection</a></li><li>Lets #HackTogether: Javascript On Azure <a href="https://dev.to/azure/lets-hacktogether-javascript-on-azure-keynote-nml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Keynote</a></li><li><a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/educator-developer-blog/step-by-step-guide-migrating-v3-to-v4-programming-model-for/ba-p/3897691?WT.mc_id=academic-98351-juliamuiruri" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Step by Step Guide: Migrating v3 to v4 programming model for Azure Functions for Node.Js Application</a></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="continue-your-journey-with-fallforintelligentapps">Continue your journey with #FallForIntelligentApps<a href="#continue-your-journey-with-fallforintelligentapps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Continue your journey with #FallForIntelligentApps" title="Direct link to Continue your journey with #FallForIntelligentApps">​</a></h2><p>Join us this Fall on a learning journey to explore building intelligent apps. Combine the power of AI, cloud-native app development, and cloud-scale data to build highly differentiated digital experiences. Develop adaptive, responsive, and personalized experiences by building and modernizing intelligent applications with Azure. Engage in a self-paced learning adventure by following along the <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/30days" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#30Days of Intelligent Apps</a> series, completing the <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA/csc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intelligent Apps Skills Challenge</a>, joining the Product Group for a live <a href="http://aka.ms/FallforIA/ATE-series" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask The Expert</a> series or building an end to end solution architecture with a live guided experience through the <a href="http://aka.ms/FallforIA/LearnLive" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn Live</a> series. Discover more <a href="https://aka.ms/FallForIA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="hands-on-practice-make-your-first-contribution-to-open-source">Hands-on practice: Make your first contribution to open source!<a href="#hands-on-practice-make-your-first-contribution-to-open-source" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hands-on practice: Make your first contribution to open source!" title="Direct link to Hands-on practice: Make your first contribution to open source!">​</a></h2><p>Join our GitHUb Discussion Forum to connect with developers from every part of world, see contributions from other, find collaborators and make your first contribution to a real-world project!
Don't forget to give the repo a star ⭐</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="resources">Resources<a href="#resources" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Resources" title="Direct link to Resources">​</a></h2><p>All resources are accessible on our <a href="https://aka.ms/JavaScripton_Azure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">landing page</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Fall-For-IA</category>
            <category>30-days-of-IA</category>
            <category>learn-live</category>
            <category>hack-together</category>
            <category>community-buzz</category>
            <category>ask-the-expert</category>
            <category>azure-kubernetes-service</category>
            <category>azure-functions</category>
            <category>azure-openai</category>
            <category>azure-container-apps</category>
            <category>azure-cosmos-db</category>
            <category>github-copilot</category>
            <category>github-codespaces</category>
            <category>github-actions</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fall is Coming! 🍂]]></title>
            <link>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/road-to-fallforIA</link>
            <guid>https://azure.github.io/Cloud-Native/30daysofIA/road-to-fallforIA</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Combine the power of AI, cloud-scale data, and cloud-native app development to create highly differentiated digital experiences. Develop adaptive, responsive, and personalized experiences by building and modernizing intelligent applications with Azure.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>September is almost here - and that can only mean one thing!! It's time to <strong>🍂 Fall for something new and exciting</strong> and spend a few weeks skilling up on relevant tools, techologies and solutions!! </p><p>Last year, we focused on #ServerlessSeptember. This year, we're building on that theme with the addition of cloud-scale <strong>Data</strong>, cloud-native <strong>Technologies</strong> and cloud-based <strong>AI</strong> integrations to help you modernize and build intelligent apps for the enterprise!</p><p>Watch this space - and join us in September to learn more!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Fall-For-IA</category>
            <category>30-days-of-IA</category>
            <category>learn-live</category>
            <category>hack-together</category>
            <category>community-buzz</category>
            <category>ask-the-expert</category>
            <category>azure-kubernetes-service</category>
            <category>azure-functions</category>
            <category>azure-openai</category>
            <category>azure-container-apps</category>
            <category>azure-cosmos-db</category>
            <category>github-copilot</category>
            <category>github-codespaces</category>
            <category>github-actions</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>